<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>linguistics on Irati Hurtado</title>
    <link>https://irhuru.github.io/tags/linguistics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in linguistics on Irati Hurtado</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 18:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://irhuru.github.io/tags/linguistics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How human-like are the linguistic abilities of ChatGPT?</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/chatgpt-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/chatgpt-language/</guid>
      <description>The arrival of ChatGPT at the end of last year has sparked a debate about how it could impact several different fields, ranging from education, to content creation, to finance and to many others. This NLP tool is the epitome of generative AI, a type of technology that “generates” content, hence the name, after being trained on large amounts of data. In this case, text data.
From a linguistic perspective, it’s exciting to see how ChatGPT outputs seem natural and convincing, leading many to assert that it behaves in a human-like way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phonetic transcription systems you should know</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/phonetic-transcription/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/phonetic-transcription/</guid>
      <description>What is phonetic transcription? Phonetic transcription is the use of phonetic symbols to represent speech. We could say it&#39;s a way to visually represent speech sounds, which is important because orthography often doesn&#39;t represent pronunciation accurately.
Each phonetic symbol represents a sound in a spoken utterance. However, which phonetic symbol we use depends on the phonetic transcription system we follow. This means that the same dataset can be transcribed in more than one way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Latex and why you need to use it for your linguistics papers</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/latex-docs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/latex-docs/</guid>
      <description>Linguistics papers often include tons of visual information, such as syntax trees, IPA symbols, glosses, and so on. These things are cool because they are helpful to convey your message, but they are sometimes hard to manage when writing your paper with a standard word processor. Who hasn&#39;t drawn a syntax tree using PowerPoint and then taken a screenshot of it to include it in a Word doc?
Fortunately, Latex exists so we don&#39;t have to deal with these issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog posts coming soon!</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/coming-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 11:04:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/coming-soon/</guid>
      <description>I will start blogging very soon.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
