<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Language on Irati Hurtado</title>
    <link>https://irhuru.github.io/tags/language/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Language on Irati Hurtado</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 18:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://irhuru.github.io/tags/language/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Can LLMs understand emojis?</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/llms-emojis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/llms-emojis/</guid>
      <description>Emojis are graphic symbols or ideograms that represent not only facial expressions, but also ideas and concepts. Emojis are extremely popular worldwide, primarily in chat and social media. They can appear as an additional element in the sentence, as in &#34;I liked the cake 😊&#34;, or replacing a word, as in &#34;I liked the 🍰&#34;.
From the perspective of large language models (LLMs), emojis are interesting because they convey a semantic as well as a pragmatic meaning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do LLMs have a personality?</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/llms-personality/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/llms-personality/</guid>
      <description>Personality is the enduring set of characteristics or qualities that form a person’s distinctive character. The science of personality has been long studied by psychologists, and multiple tests have been designed to assess personality constructs.
Interestingly, many of these tests follow a linguistic approach, since they are based on a factor analysis of the language used to describe behavior. For example, if someone says they like to “have everything organized and planned”, that would correlate with a conscientious personality trait.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is learning a programming language similar to learning a natural language?</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/programming-languages/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/programming-languages/</guid>
      <description>Programming languages are systems of notation used for writing computer programs (e.g., Java), whereas natural languages are systems of communication that have developed naturally in human communities (e.g., French). Despite both of them being languages, little is known about whether learning a programming language is similar to learning a natural language.
What does the research say? Traditionally, learning programming languages has been associated with mathematical skills. In fact, this is what happens in most STEM degrees, where students are required to have a solid background in algebra, calculus, and other branches of mathematics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Have LLMs developed Theory of Mind?</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/theory-of-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/theory-of-mind/</guid>
      <description>If you are into psychology, you have probably heard about Theory of Mind before. Theory of Mind is the ability to attribute mental states, such as beliefs, emotions, or desires, to oneself and others. It basically is the human ability to interpret what is going on in someone else&#39;s head. As you can imagine, Theory of Mind is an important cognitive skill needed for proper social interaction.
Despite its importance, humans are not born with Theory of Mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How human-like are the linguistic abilities of ChatGPT?</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/chatgpt-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/chatgpt-language/</guid>
      <description>The arrival of ChatGPT at the end of last year has sparked a debate about how it could impact several different fields, ranging from education, to content creation, to finance and to many others. This NLP tool is the epitome of generative AI, a type of technology that “generates” content, hence the name, after being trained on large amounts of data. In this case, text data.
From a linguistic perspective, it’s exciting to see how ChatGPT outputs seem natural and convincing, leading many to assert that it behaves in a human-like way.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
