<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HCI on Irati Hurtado</title>
    <link>https://irhuru.github.io/tags/hci/</link>
    <description>Recent content in HCI on Irati Hurtado</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 18:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://irhuru.github.io/tags/hci/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Can we make LLMs learn in a more human-like way?</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/language-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/language-learning/</guid>
      <description>The difference between artificial intelligence (AI) and human intelligence is well known: whereas humans use their brain, their memory, and other cognitive abilities, AI uses data provided by humans. In fact, AI uses a lot of data. For example, large language models (LLMs), a type of generative AI, are trained on huge amounts of data. The Common Crawl archive, which is LLMs&#39; primary source of data, contains around 3 billion web pages and 400 TB of unocmpressed data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can computers change the way we speak?</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/computer-speak/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/computer-speak/</guid>
      <description>Some months ago, I bought my first smart speaker: an Amazon echo. Because I live in the U.S., Alexa&#39;s default language was English. Even though I&#39;m a native speaker of Spanish, I can also speak English, so it wasn&#39;t really a problem for me. However, when pronouncing Spanish proper names (e.g., people or places), I would still use my Spanish pronunciation. It turns out Alexa couldn&#39;t understand me unless I anglicized those names (ugh!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
