<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>audio on Irati Hurtado</title>
    <link>https://irhuru.github.io/tags/audio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in audio on Irati Hurtado</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 18:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://irhuru.github.io/tags/audio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Transcribing and analyzing speech samples with CLAN</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/clan-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/clan-software/</guid>
      <description>In a previous blog post, I wrote about automatic transcription software that you can use to speed up your transcription process. However, chances are that you also want to analyze what you transcribe if you&#39;re working on a research project. Measures such as words per minute or lexical diversity scores are quite common in linguistics research. In this blog post, I introduce you to CLAN, a software that will help you with both transcription and analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic transcription software to transcribe like a pro</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/automatic-transcription/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/automatic-transcription/</guid>
      <description>Chances are that if you are working on a linguistics project, you might have to transcribe audio recordings in order to analyze them. Transcribing can be a deadly boring process, especially if you have many files or if you are dealing with speakers of non-standard dialects/varieties.
However, recent advancements in automatic speech recognition (ASR) have led to the development of very cool software that can help you speed up the transcription process.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
