<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>conversation on Irati Hurtado</title>
    <link>https://irhuru.github.io/tags/conversation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in conversation on Irati Hurtado</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 18:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://irhuru.github.io/tags/conversation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The little-known history of synthetic voices</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/ai-voices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/ai-voices/</guid>
      <description>Synthetic voices, or artificial voices, are part of our lives (who has never talked to iPhone&#39;s Siri, Amazon Alexa, or Microsoft Cortana?). Conversational AI, which largely relies on these synthetic voices, is currently experiencing a boom and its market is expected to grow even more in the next four years.
However, even though synthetic voices might look like a very new invention, the truth is that they have been around for a long, long time (more than 200 years, actually!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is there a need to anthropomorphize language technologies?</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/anthropomorphism-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/anthropomorphism-language/</guid>
      <description>Some weeks ago, we heard about Blake Lemoine, a Google engineer who claimed that LaMDA, a chatbot that can carry unstructured conversations with people, had a &#39;human soul&#39;. He came to this conclusion after having long, deep conversations with LaMDA, which he later shared with The Washington Post.
What&#39;s striking about this case is that an engineer, who&#39;s supposed to have a thorough technical knowledge about how chatbots work, was fooled into believing the chatbot was actually human!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>