<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>corpus on Irati Hurtado</title>
    <link>https://irhuru.github.io/tags/corpus/</link>
    <description>Recent content in corpus on Irati Hurtado</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2022 18:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://irhuru.github.io/tags/corpus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>An introduction to Voyant Tools for corpus analysis</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/voyant-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2022 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/voyant-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp;
If you&amp;rsquo;re into the Digital Humanities, you probably know about the importance of text analysis. Whereas programming languages such as Python or R allow you to do this efficiently, some people prefer to use tools which don&amp;rsquo;t require any coding skills 👨🏻‍💻. A good example of such a tool is Voyant Tools, an open-source web-based application for text analysis. In this blog post, I will show you the basics of using Voyant Tools to analyze a corpus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A simple guide to using AntConc for corpus analysis</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/antconc-corpus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2022 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/antconc-corpus/</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp;
If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in corpus linguistics, you probably know that some of the things this field involves includes searching for patterns in a group of texts (e.g., find frequent words or collocations). This can be easily done using a programming language like Python or R 👩🏻‍💻. But, what if you don&amp;rsquo;t have much experience with programming languages? Well, this is where a tool like AntConc becomes useful!
AntConc is a free corpus analysis software that can easily help you identify patterns in a collection of texts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Four key steps for developing guidelines for language data annotation</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/data-annotation-guidelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/data-annotation-guidelines/</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp;
Whether you want to build a corpus to document an interesting linguistic phenomenon or simply want to have language data to train your AI models, the process of data annotation is crucial.
Language data annotation (or text data annotation) is the process of adding labels with relevant information or meta-data. Even though it might seem like a simple process, choosing the right labels for your data is not always easy, as ambiguous data is pretty common 😣.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An analysis of Peter Pan using the R package koRpus</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/korpus-peterpan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/korpus-peterpan/</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp;
If you are into language research, you probably use R to analyze your data 📊. One of the good things about R is that you can install packages to extend R&amp;rsquo;s basic functions. In this blog post, I&amp;rsquo;d like to introduce you to a very useful package for language research: koRpus.
Despite its name, the R package koRpus was designed to work with individual texts, and not with a collection of texts (I know, this is confusing!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>