<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Irati Hurtado</title>
    <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Irati Hurtado</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 18:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://irhuru.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Four key steps for developing guidelines for language data annotation</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/data-annotation-guidelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/data-annotation-guidelines/</guid>
      <description>Whether you want to build a corpus to document an interesting linguistic phenomenon or simply want to have language data to train your AI models, the process of data annotation is crucial.
Language data annotation (or text data annotation) is the process of adding labels with relevant information or meta-data. Even though it might seem like a simple process, choosing the right labels for your data is not always easy, as ambiguous data is pretty common 😣.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to get Twitter data</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/twitter-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/twitter-data/</guid>
      <description>Nowadays, a lot of linguistics research uses language data from Twitter. At every major linguistics conference, there&amp;rsquo;s at least one or two people (if not more!) discussing the use of language on this popular social network. Even though doing research on language use on Twitter is quite trendy now, getting the data for research is not that cool. The reason behind this? There are several ways to get Twitter data and each way depends on a variety of factors, which makes the process a bit confusing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Latex and why you need to use it for your linguistics papers</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/latex-docs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/latex-docs/</guid>
      <description>Linguistics papers often include tons of visual information, such as syntax trees, IPA symbols, glosses, and so on. These things are cool because they are helpful to convey your message, but they are sometimes hard to manage when writing your paper with a standard word processor. Who hasn&amp;rsquo;t drawn a syntax tree using PowerPoint and then taken a screenshot of it to include it in a Word doc? 🙄
Fortunately, Latex exists so we don&amp;rsquo;t have to deal with these issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An analysis of Peter Pan using the R package koRpus</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/korpus-peterpan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/korpus-peterpan/</guid>
      <description>If you are into language research, you probably use R to analyze your data 📊. One of the good things about R is that you can install packages to extend R&amp;rsquo;s basic functions. In this blog post, I&amp;rsquo;d like to introduce you to a very useful package for language research: koRpus.
Despite its name, the R package koRpus was designed to work with individual texts, and not with a collection of texts (I know, this is confusing!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transcribing and analyzing speech samples with CLAN</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/clan-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/clan-software/</guid>
      <description>In a previous blog post, I wrote about automatic transcription software that you can use to speed up your transcription process. However, chances are that you also want to analyze what you transcribe if you&amp;rsquo;re working on a research project. Measures such as words per minute or lexical diversity scores are quite common in linguistics research. In this blog post, I introduce you to CLAN, a software that will help you with both transcription and analysis 👇🏻.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic transcription software to transcribe like a pro</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/automatic-transcription/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/automatic-transcription/</guid>
      <description>Chances are that if you are working on a linguistics project, you might have to transcribe audio recordings in order to analyze them. Transcribing can be a deadly boring process 😩, especially if you have many files or if you are dealing with speakers of non-standard dialects/varieties.
However, recent advancements in automatic speech recognition (ASR) have led to the development of very cool software that can help you speed up the transcription process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A short guide to building a Twitter bot</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/twitter-bot/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/twitter-bot/</guid>
      <description>I recently discovered the fascinating world of Twitter bots (what&amp;rsquo;s that?). Isn&amp;rsquo;t it amazing that a simple computer program can post random stuff on Twitter all by itself? 😎✨ It probably isn&amp;rsquo;t, considering that we&amp;rsquo;re in the middle of a tech revolution, but they&amp;rsquo;re fun to build, so that&amp;rsquo;s a good enough reason to waste your time creating one!
In this guide, I explain you how to build a Twitter bot from scratch step by step.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a Haiku generator with Python</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/haiku-generator/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/haiku-generator/</guid>
      <description>What is a haiku? I&amp;rsquo;m sure you have heard the term haiku at least once in your life. Haiku is a type of short form poetry that originated in Japan 🇯🇵. These pieces of poetry consist of three phrases, where the first and third line have 5 syllables each and the second one has 7 syllables. This makes a total of 17 syllables per poem which follow a 5-7-5 pattern.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using machine learning to build a dialect classifier</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/dialect-classifier/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/dialect-classifier/</guid>
      <description>As a linguist, I have always been curious about how computers can make sense of texts that combine different languages or language varieties. Therefore, I decided to learn more about this and implemented a dialect classifier. That is, an algorithm that would take some text as input and would determine the language variety (or dialect) it represents. To find out how I did it, read this post or take a look at this Jupyter notebook with all the code!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Amazon Mechanical Turk to conduct linguistic research</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/amazon-mechanical-turk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/amazon-mechanical-turk/</guid>
      <description>As a linguist, I often need to find speakers from a particular country or region to gather data on how they say something. However, it can sometimes be difficult to find a large group of speakers from a region you have never been to. In those cases, Amazon Mechanical Turk can come in handy. In this blog post, I explain how you can start using this awesome tool for your linguistic research!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to create stunning presentations using Reveal.js in R</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/revealjs-r-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/revealjs-r-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>I recently found out about an R package that allows you to create Reveal.js presentations in R using RMarkdown syntax. If you are like me and love to display cool graphs in your slides, don&amp;rsquo;t miss this short tutorial!
Why you need to start using Reveal.js in R Okay, so you already know how to use PowerPoint. Why using something different then? 🤔 There are many reasons, actually, but one of them is that PowerPoint doesn&amp;rsquo;t allow you to display interactive graphs in your presentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog posts coming soon!</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/coming-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 11:04:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/coming-soon/</guid>
      <description>I will start blogging very soon.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>