<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Irati Hurtado</title>
    <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Irati Hurtado</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 18:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://irhuru.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Can LLMs understand emojis?</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/llms-emojis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/llms-emojis/</guid>
      <description>Emojis are graphic symbols or ideograms that represent not only facial expressions, but also ideas and concepts. Emojis are extremely popular worldwide, primarily in chat and social media. They can appear as an additional element in the sentence, as in &#34;I liked the cake 😊&#34;, or replacing a word, as in &#34;I liked the 🍰&#34;.
From the perspective of large language models (LLMs), emojis are interesting because they convey a semantic as well as a pragmatic meaning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talking to machines: A brief history of chatbots</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/history-chatbots/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/history-chatbots/</guid>
      <description>Chatbots, although a trendy product now, have existed for decades. Advances in AI have transformed chatbots from simple and rule-based systems to more complex and sophisticated conversational agents. Let’s dive into the history of chatbots, from their beginnings to the modern AI-driven companions we see today.
ELIZA: The first chatbot (1966) ELIZA was the first chatbot, developed by professor Joseph Weizenbaum at MIT. ELIZA was designed to mimic a psychotherapist, responding to users&#39; messages with pre-defined responses using pattern matching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do LLMs have a personality?</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/llms-personality/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/llms-personality/</guid>
      <description>Personality is the enduring set of characteristics or qualities that form a person’s distinctive character. The science of personality has been long studied by psychologists, and multiple tests have been designed to assess personality constructs.
Interestingly, many of these tests follow a linguistic approach, since they are based on a factor analysis of the language used to describe behavior. For example, if someone says they like to “have everything organized and planned”, that would correlate with a conscientious personality trait.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is learning a programming language similar to learning a natural language?</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/programming-languages/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/programming-languages/</guid>
      <description>Programming languages are systems of notation used for writing computer programs (e.g., Java), whereas natural languages are systems of communication that have developed naturally in human communities (e.g., French). Despite both of them being languages, little is known about whether learning a programming language is similar to learning a natural language.
What does the research say? Traditionally, learning programming languages has been associated with mathematical skills. In fact, this is what happens in most STEM degrees, where students are required to have a solid background in algebra, calculus, and other branches of mathematics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is there a preference for female voices in AI virtual assistants?</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/gendered-ai-assistants/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/gendered-ai-assistants/</guid>
      <description>If you ask Amazon Alexa if it is a woman, it will answer &#34;I&#39;m not a woman, I&#39;m an AI&#34;. In fact, the majority of AI virtual assistants are designed to be genderless (think of AI virtual assistants like Siri, Cortana, or Google Assistant). After all, they are simply made of code. Surprisingly, most of these AI virtual assistants use clear female voices when interacting with users. But, why is that?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Have LLMs developed Theory of Mind?</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/theory-of-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/theory-of-mind/</guid>
      <description>If you are into psychology, you have probably heard about Theory of Mind before. Theory of Mind is the ability to attribute mental states, such as beliefs, emotions, or desires, to oneself and others. It basically is the human ability to interpret what is going on in someone else&#39;s head. As you can imagine, Theory of Mind is an important cognitive skill needed for proper social interaction.
Despite its importance, humans are not born with Theory of Mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can we make LLMs learn in a more human-like way?</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/language-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/language-learning/</guid>
      <description>The difference between artificial intelligence (AI) and human intelligence is well known: whereas humans use their brain, their memory, and other cognitive abilities, AI uses data provided by humans. In fact, AI uses a lot of data. For example, large language models (LLMs), a type of generative AI, are trained on huge amounts of data. The Common Crawl archive, which is LLMs&#39; primary source of data, contains around 3 billion web pages and 400 TB of unocmpressed data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are there standards for the annotation of language corpora?</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/language-corpora-annotation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2023 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/language-corpora-annotation/</guid>
      <description>Some weeks ago, I attended a conference where several of the presenters discussed language corpora they had created as part of different research projects. During the Q&amp;A turn of the last presenter, an award-winning researcher and creator of various corpora, one of the attendees raised their hand and asked: “I have attended five talks today discussing language corpora and each corpus employed different annotation schemes. Wouldn’t it be convenient to have a set of standards for corpus annotation that everyone could use?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How human-like are the linguistic abilities of ChatGPT?</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/chatgpt-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/chatgpt-language/</guid>
      <description>The arrival of ChatGPT at the end of last year has sparked a debate about how it could impact several different fields, ranging from education, to content creation, to finance and to many others. This NLP tool is the epitome of generative AI, a type of technology that “generates” content, hence the name, after being trained on large amounts of data. In this case, text data.
From a linguistic perspective, it’s exciting to see how ChatGPT outputs seem natural and convincing, leading many to assert that it behaves in a human-like way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring textual data using R Shiny</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/rshiny-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/rshiny-data/</guid>
      <description>In previous blog posts, I discussed the use of software such as AntConc or Voyant to analyze corpus data. Even though these are very helpful, you can only use them to perform the range of default analyses they offer. But, what if you need more customization? Maybe you want to create your own graphs or explore your data in ways that go beyond traditional KWIC analyses and basic word frequencies. Well, then keep reading because that is totally possible!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An introduction to Voyant Tools for corpus analysis</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/voyant-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2022 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/voyant-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>If you&#39;re into the Digital Humanities, you probably know about the importance of text analysis. Whereas programming languages such as Python or R allow you to do this efficiently, some people prefer to use tools which don&#39;t require any coding skills. A good example of such a tool is Voyant Tools, an open-source web-based application for text analysis. In this blog post, I will show you the basics of using Voyant Tools to analyze a corpus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The little-known history of synthetic voices</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/ai-voices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/ai-voices/</guid>
      <description>Synthetic voices, or artificial voices, are part of our lives (who has never talked to iPhone&#39;s Siri, Amazon Alexa, or Microsoft Cortana?). Conversational AI, which largely relies on these synthetic voices, is currently experiencing a boom and its market is expected to grow even more in the next four years.
However, even though synthetic voices might look like a very new invention, the truth is that they have been around for a long, long time (more than 200 years, actually!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A simple guide to using AntConc for corpus analysis</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/antconc-corpus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2022 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/antconc-corpus/</guid>
      <description>If you&#39;re interested in corpus linguistics, you probably know that some of the things this field involves includes searching for patterns in a group of texts (e.g., find frequent words or collocations). This can be easily done using a programming language like Python or R. But, what if you don&#39;t have much experience with programming languages? Well, this is where a tool like AntConc becomes useful!
AntConc is a free corpus analysis software that can easily help you identify patterns in a collection of texts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is there a need to anthropomorphize language technologies?</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/anthropomorphism-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/anthropomorphism-language/</guid>
      <description>Some weeks ago, we heard about Blake Lemoine, a Google engineer who claimed that LaMDA, a chatbot that can carry unstructured conversations with people, had a &#39;human soul&#39;. He came to this conclusion after having long, deep conversations with LaMDA, which he later shared with The Washington Post.
What&#39;s striking about this case is that an engineer, who&#39;s supposed to have a thorough technical knowledge about how chatbots work, was fooled into believing the chatbot was actually human!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phonetic transcription systems you should know</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/phonetic-transcription/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/phonetic-transcription/</guid>
      <description>What is phonetic transcription? Phonetic transcription is the use of phonetic symbols to represent speech. We could say it&#39;s a way to visually represent speech sounds, which is important because orthography often doesn&#39;t represent pronunciation accurately.
Each phonetic symbol represents a sound in a spoken utterance. However, which phonetic symbol we use depends on the phonetic transcription system we follow. This means that the same dataset can be transcribed in more than one way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can computers change the way we speak?</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/computer-speak/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/computer-speak/</guid>
      <description>Some months ago, I bought my first smart speaker: an Amazon echo. Because I live in the U.S., Alexa&#39;s default language was English. Even though I&#39;m a native speaker of Spanish, I can also speak English, so it wasn&#39;t really a problem for me. However, when pronouncing Spanish proper names (e.g., people or places), I would still use my Spanish pronunciation. It turns out Alexa couldn&#39;t understand me unless I anglicized those names (ugh!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Four key steps for developing guidelines for language data annotation</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/data-annotation-guidelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/data-annotation-guidelines/</guid>
      <description>Whether you want to build a corpus to document an interesting linguistic phenomenon or simply want to have language data to train your AI models, the process of data annotation is crucial.
Language data annotation (or text data annotation) is the process of adding labels with relevant information or meta-data. Even though it might seem like a simple process, choosing the right labels for your data is not always easy, as ambiguous data is pretty common.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to get Twitter data</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/twitter-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/twitter-data/</guid>
      <description>Nowadays, a lot of linguistics research uses language data from Twitter. At every major linguistics conference, there&#39;s at least one or two people (if not more!) discussing the use of language on this popular social network. Even though doing research on language use on Twitter is quite trendy now, getting the data for research is not that cool. The reason behind this? There are several ways to get Twitter data and each way depends on a variety of factors, which makes the process a bit confusing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An analysis of Peter Pan using the R package koRpus</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/korpus-peterpan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/korpus-peterpan/</guid>
      <description>If you are into language research, you probably use R to analyze your data. One of the good things about R is that you can install packages to extend R&#39;s basic functions. In this blog post, I&#39;d like to introduce you to a very useful package for language research: koRpus.
Despite its name, the R package koRpus was designed to work with individual texts, and not with a collection of texts (I know, this is confusing!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transcribing and analyzing speech samples with CLAN</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/clan-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/clan-software/</guid>
      <description>In a previous blog post, I wrote about automatic transcription software that you can use to speed up your transcription process. However, chances are that you also want to analyze what you transcribe if you&#39;re working on a research project. Measures such as words per minute or lexical diversity scores are quite common in linguistics research. In this blog post, I introduce you to CLAN, a software that will help you with both transcription and analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A short guide to building a Twitter bot</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/twitter-bot/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/twitter-bot/</guid>
      <description>I recently discovered the fascinating world of Twitter bots (what&#39;s that?). Isn&#39;t it amazing that a simple computer program can post random stuff on Twitter all by itself? It probably isn&#39;t, considering that we&#39;re in the middle of a tech revolution, but they&#39;re fun to build, so that&#39;s a good enough reason to waste your time creating one!
In this guide, I explain you how to build a Twitter bot from scratch step by step.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a Haiku generator with Python</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/haiku-generator/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/haiku-generator/</guid>
      <description>What is a haiku? I&#39;m sure you have heard the term haiku at least once in your life. Haiku is a type of short form poetry that originated in Japan. These pieces of poetry consist of three phrases, where the first and third line have 5 syllables each and the second one has 7 syllables. This makes a total of 17 syllables per poem which follow a 5-7-5 pattern.
Haikus have become popular in other cultures too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using machine learning to build a dialect classifier</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/dialect-classifier/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/dialect-classifier/</guid>
      <description>As a linguist, I have always been curious about how computers can make sense of texts that combine different languages or language varieties. Therefore, I decided to learn more about this and implemented a dialect classifier. That is, an algorithm that would take some text as input and would determine the language variety (or dialect) it represents. To find out how I did it, read this post or take a look at this Jupyter notebook with all the code!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Amazon Mechanical Turk to conduct linguistic research</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/amazon-mechanical-turk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/amazon-mechanical-turk/</guid>
      <description>As a linguist, I often need to find speakers from a particular country or region to gather data on how they say something. However, it can sometimes be difficult to find a large group of speakers from a region you have never been to. In those cases, Amazon Mechanical Turk can come in handy. In this blog post, I explain how you can start using this awesome tool for your linguistic research!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to create stunning presentations using Reveal.js in R</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/revealjs-r-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/revealjs-r-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>I recently found out about an R package that allows you to create Reveal.js presentations in R using RMarkdown syntax. If you are like me and love to display cool graphs in your slides, don&#39;t miss this short tutorial!
Why you need to start using Reveal.js in R Okay, so you already know how to use PowerPoint. Why using something different then? There are many reasons, actually, but one of them is that PowerPoint doesn&#39;t allow you to display interactive graphs in your presentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog posts coming soon!</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/coming-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 11:04:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/coming-soon/</guid>
      <description>I will start blogging very soon.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
