<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>data on Irati Hurtado</title>
    <link>https://irhuru.github.io/tags/data/</link>
    <description>Recent content in data on Irati Hurtado</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 18:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://irhuru.github.io/tags/data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Four key steps for developing guidelines for language data annotation</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/data-annotation-guidelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/data-annotation-guidelines/</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp;
Whether you want to build a corpus to document an interesting linguistic phenomenon or simply want to have language data to train your AI models, the process of data annotation is crucial.
Language data annotation (or text data annotation) is the process of adding labels with relevant information or meta-data. Even though it might seem like a simple process, choosing the right labels for your data is not always easy, as ambiguous data is pretty common 😣.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to get Twitter data</title>
      <link>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/twitter-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irhuru.github.io/blog/twitter-data/</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp;
Nowadays, a lot of linguistics research uses language data from Twitter. At every major linguistics conference, there&amp;rsquo;s at least one or two people (if not more!) discussing the use of language on this popular social network. Even though doing research on language use on Twitter is quite trendy now, getting the data for research is not that cool. The reason behind this? There are several ways to get Twitter data and each way depends on a variety of factors, which makes the process a bit confusing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>